

PARVATHY VAZHOOR WEB DEVELOPER

parvathyvd@gmail.com

3 604-358-3962

in linkedin.com/in/parvathy-vazhoor

odepen.io/parvathyvd

github.com/parvathyvd

PORTFOLIO

realwordpressdevelopment.com/webfolio

EDUCATION

Bachelors Degree in Computer Science

Vidya Academy of Science & Technology, India

LANGUAGES

English

Hindi

OTHER INTERESTS

Biking

Glass Painting

Dancing

CONTACT ADDRESS

8277 161st Surrey BC, V4N0N3

CAREER PROFILE

I am a web developer specializing in Front end development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including PHP, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, PHP(Codeigniter) and Vanila Javascript(Jquery,React). Strong background in Wordpress web development and design.

WORK HISTORY

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER (FREELANCER)

REALWORDPRESSDEVELOPMENT (09/2020 to Present)

Developed web apps using HTML5,CSS3 and Javascript(React)

Developed websites using PHP, Bootstrap and Javascript

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

RSTINSTRUMENTS (09/2018 Sep to 09/2020)

Responsible for redeveloping the RST website

upgraded the HTML website to custom PHP website and MYSQL database with newer design. Designed and developed website using PHP, HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript ES6

Migrated and redeveloped the entire website with same design in to the Wordpress

WEB DEVELOPER/DESIGNER

BRIKERS (05/2017 to 07/2018)

Developed Brikers website wireframe using Lucidchart.

Developed brikers website using Codeigniter(PHP framework), Bootstrap and jquery. Used SASS preprocessor.

Tested webpage for responsiveness and adjusted the media queries accordingly.

WEB DEVELOPER/DESIGNER

ENGAGEMEDIA (10/2012 to 02/2017)

Responsible for all stages of Web site creations for client, from initial design and architecture to development, deployment, and management.

Developed websites mainly **Wordpress CMS**. Responsible for Domain registration, Webhosting, Wordpress, theme, plugin installation and customization.

Developed custom wordpress templates

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

ABSOLUTE NATURAL PRODUCTS (Freelance 09/2016 to 10/2016)

Responsible for all stages of Web site development. Wordpress Web design/development, Social Media, SEO, Business Card design and Office 365 email configuration. Hosted the domain and installed the WordPress CMS. Added necessary plugins and Customized the website.

WEB DEVELOPER

BUSINESS ASSIST CANADA(06/2014 to 11/2014)

Responsible for all stages of Web site development. Web design/development, Social Media, SEO, Graphic Card design and Office 365 email configuration.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

PHP7, Codeigniter WordPress HTML5, CSS3 (SASS,SCSS) Bootstrap Javascript ES6 & Jquery React Npm, Webpack & Babel **MYSQL** Lucidchart Photoshop CC 2017,Illustrator Git & Github & Terminal **Email Marketing & SEO** Google Search Console Google Tag Manager Godaddy & Hostgator Mailchimp Filezila VSC, Phpstorm, Atom, Coda2, Dreamweaver **MAMP**